# **Trevor Kelly**

★ trevork.dev trevor.daniel.kelly@gmail.com TrevorDKelly Pittsburgh, PA

### **Profile**

I am a software engineer with multiple years of experience in JavaScript (ES6), Ruby, Go, and multiple frameworks. I am a co-creator of Chimera  $\mathscr{D}$ , which automates canary deployments for containerized microservices that communicate via a service mesh on AWS.

## **Experience**

**Co-Creator, Software Engineer,** Chimera - https://chimera-deploy.dev *∂* 

2022 - present Remote

- Researched, designed, prototyped, and implemented Chimera, an open-source tool for performing automated canary deployments of containerized microservices
- Automated a deployment process that involves manipulating multiple AWS services concurrently
- Configured CloudWatch and Prometheus to monitor traffic flowing through a newly released microservice
- Automated the rollback process based off of production metrics data
- Utilized AWS's Software Development Kit to interact with and manipulate cloud infrastructure
- Created server-sent events stream to pass live updates and metrics data charts to a React front end
- Built a containerized microservice production infrastructure hosted on AWS for development testing
- Designed workflow and infrastructure diagrams
- Collaborated with a remote team spread across four different cities
- Authored a comprehensive technical case study documenting design decisions
- Presented a live tech talk describing the project

## **Software Engineer**, Self-Employed

2019 - 2022

 Developed personal projects and open-source software using Node.js, Express, Ruby, Sinatra, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, Redis, React/Redux, vanilla JavaScript, HTML, and CSS Remote

- Monkeys Typing Hamlet
  - Monkey hands randomly typing on a keyboard, tracking whether they type Hamlet
  - Google Cloud VPS hosted, NGINX reverse proxy, and Node express app with MongoDB and Redis
- Requestotron
  - Webhook and HTTP request visualizer for viewing and debugging network communication
  - Node express app with PostgreSQL and MongoDB databases
- DOM-Keyboard
  - In-browser interactive keyboard built out of DOM nodes and released as an npm package
  - Zero dependency Javascript using promise syntax for chain-able method calls with OOP design

#### **Operations Manager**, Castleview Partners

2016 - 2020

Chicago

# **Skills**

Languages	Frameworks	Technologies	Cloud
Javascript, ES6, Ruby, Go,	Express, Sinatra,	Git, GitHub, Docker,	AWS: ECS, ECR, Fargate,
SQL, HTML, CSS	React/Redux, Node,	CI/CD, HTTP, REST APIs,	App Mesh, CloudWatch
	Handlebars, jQuery	NGINX, Redis, MongoDB	Google Cloud VPS

#### **Education**

# Launch School, Software Engineering

2019 - 2022

Multi-year, mastery-based software engineering curriculum with progression gated by written exams and live coding interviews to develop problem-solving skills. LaunchSchool.com/employers &

Westfield State University, BA in Communications

2008 - 2012